♬～
Rome
(ｼﾞｮｾﾌ)何だ？ こりゃ～！
What the hell is this?!
Trying to feed me spaghetti somebody dropped their pen in, huh?!
このホテルは
インク入りスパゲッティを➡
食わせようってのか？
ああ～ん!?
(給仕)い… いいえ お客様
これは ネーロといいまして➡
N-No sir... This is pasta with Nero sauce,
which gets its color from fresh squid ink.
新鮮なイカの墨が 入っているので
黒いんでございますよ｡
何～!?
(給仕)おいピーですよ｡
What?
It's quite good!
へ～｡
うわっ！
(ｼｰｻﾞｰ)ん？
ふん！
おっ… ん…｡
はっ！
うまい！ うめえじゃあねえか！
Tasty! It's so good!
ほっ…｡
いけるぜ グー！
It's just great!
最近 このホテルも
格が落ちたようだな…｡
Standards have sunk so low at this hotel.
田舎者が増えたようだ｡
They'll let in the most tasteless people.
ん？
Signorina, I have a gift for you.
シニョリーナ…
これは 君へのプレゼントだよ｡
(女性)わあ！ 美しい！
How beautiful!
かわいい人…
毎晩 ベッドに入る前➡
Every night, before you go to bed,
I'd like you to think of me when you take this off.
これを 外すとき
僕を思い出してほしいんだ｡
Oh no!
オーノー！
How can this lecher say all that with a straight face?!
あのキザ野郎！ 真顔で
あんなせりふを しゃべったぜ！
The garbage he's spewing is making my nose burn!
歯が ガタガタ浮くぜ バカ野郎！
さあ 受け取っておくれ｡
Now, please take it...
I'll enchant this... and it will make you fall under the spell of my love.
おまじないをするよ｡
君に 愛の魔法がかかるように｡
ぎゃぱ～！
I hate guys like this!
俺… ああいうやつ
大っ嫌いなんだもんね！
ふん…｡
そして 君の唇にも
魔法がかかるように…｡
Now let's see if I can enchant those lovely lips...
That jerk!
あ～ あの野郎！
当てつけやがって
あんなことしようとしている！
I can't believe he's so desperate to score!
許せん！
Enough!
All right...
よ～し｡
コォー…｡
A nasty use for the Ripple, eh?
波紋の悪用ね！
顔に巻きつけて しばらく
取れねえようにしてやるぜ！
I'll wrap these around his face to show him his place for a while!
ヘヘ…｡
なっ!?
くっ！
ううっ！
こ… これは まさか!?
I-Impossible!
は… 波紋だ！ あいつ 波紋を！
The Ripple! That was a Ripple!
(給仕)失礼します｡
Pardon me...
スピードワゴンという方から
お電話です｡
You have a call from someone named Speedwagon, Mr. Caesar Zeppeli.
シーザー･ツェペリ様｡
ママミーヤ 今 行くよ｡
Mama Mia... Well then, let's go.
W-What?!
な… 何!?
あの スケコマシ キザ野郎が➡
You mean that womanizing creep is the Zeppeli we're here to see?!
俺たちの 会いに来た
ツェペリだと!?
ふん！
♬(ｵｰﾌﾟﾆﾝｸﾞﾃｰﾏ)
♬ 静寂の底から
Shijima no soko kara
From out of the stillness
Original Translation:
Mudasubs
Timing:
Fadeout4
Mezameru sono hashira tachi
The Pillars of the past are awakening
♬ 目覚めるその柱たち 時を越え
Editor:
Tonitonichopchop
Toki wo koe
To the dawn of a new day
Editor:
Tonitonichopchop
♬ 深紅の血潮が
Shinku no chishio ga
The river of crimson blood within you
Fadeout4
Typesetting:
Mazrim
Quality Check:
♬ 立ち上がる勇気を
Tachiagaru yuuki wo hikiawaseru
Carries with it the courage to stand and fight
♬ 惹きあわせる
Uketsugu ai wo sadame to yobu nara
Even if the love I feel is just part of my legacy...
♬ 受け継ぐ愛を 宿命と呼ぶなら
♬ 微笑む目で 次の手を
Hohoemu me de tsugi no te wo
I'll still be smiling as I stay one step ahead
♬ 闇を欺いて
刹那を躱して
Yami wo azamuite setsuna wo kawashite
Defying the darkness and dodging death at every turn
Encoding:
Fadeout4
♬ 刃すり抜け奴らの間隙を突け
Yaiba surinuke yatsura no suki wo tsuke
Slipping past the knife's edge and striking when you least expect
♬ つらぬいた信念が 未来を拓く
Tsuranuita omoi ga mirai wo hiraku
The emotions running through me blaze a path to the future...
Raw Hunter: WRRRRY
♬ Like a Bloody Storm
熱くLike a Bloody Stone
Raw Hunter: WRRRRY
Like a bloody storm
Atsuku like a bloody storm
Burning like a bloody storm
♬ 血脈に
刻まれた因縁に
Ketsumyaku ni kizamareta innen ni
When the time comes to end the vendetta carried by our blood
Distro:
ExWizzard
♬ 浮き上がる消えない誇りの絆
Ukiagaru kienai hokori no kizuna
Remember that the bonds of pride will carry you through any storm
♬ 握りしめて
Nigirishimete
So hold them close
http://www.some-stuffs.com
Episode 14: "The Ultimate Warriors of an Ancient Age"
(ﾅﾚｰｼｮﾝ)
〈スピードワゴン財団｡➡
The Speedwagon Foundation.
An organization founded by Speedwagon with
the wealth he earned in the oil industry.
28年前 スピードワゴンは
石油で築いた 財力で➡
Speedwagon Foundation Headquarters, Washington DC
この財団を 設立した〉
〈人類の福利厚生のため｡➡
Their aim is to better mankind by furthering medical science in
pharmaceuticals, photochemistry, and several other disciplines.
医学 薬学 考古学など➡
さまざまな分野を 助成することが
その目的である〉
However, the Foundation's true purpose...
〈しかし 財団の 真の目的は…〉
...is to uncover the mysteries of the stone mask!
〈石仮面の謎を
追うことにある！〉
The sample is being bathed in ultraviolet light,
so please wear this protective mask.
(研究者１)
紫外線を照射しています｡➡
マスクを着けてください｡
All right, release the snake!
(研究者２)よし 蛇を出せ！
(研究者２･研究者３)おおっ！
(研究者３)蛇が吸収された！
The snake was absorbed!
Santana isn't dead! He only turned to stone to protect himself!
(研究者４)サンタナは
死んだわけではない！➡
岩となって
ガードしているにすぎない！➡
He'd be moving again if it weren't for the light!
闇にすれば 再び 動きだします！
(研究者２)考えられん！➡
Unbelievable! So how do we kill him?
どうやったら死ぬのだ!?
こいつは｡
He not only devours humans, but vampires of the stone mask as well!
(研究者３)
人間はおろか 石仮面をかぶった
吸血鬼さえ 食料にして➡
And if he's immortal...
しかも 不死身とは！
(研究者４)ですが
スピードワゴン様 ご安心を｡➡
But Mr. Speedwagon, don't worry.
このまま
紫外線を 人工照射している限り➡
As long as we continue to keep his remains
under ultraviolet light, Santana will be unable to move.
サンタナは
動くことはできません！
(研究者３)ハハハ そうですな｡
Precisely!
What a relief...
(研究者２)いや～ 一安心 一安心｡
I suppose we'll have as much time as we need to deal with him.
(研究者５)ゆっくりと こいつを
倒す方法を 研究するとしますか｡
(研究者たち)おお…｡
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)これは➡
This photograph of Santana was taken in Mexico
while he was inside of the ruins where we found him.
サンタナを発見した メキシコの
洞窟で撮影されたものだ｡
よく見たまえ！
(研究者たち)おおっ！
Look closely.
(研究者５)ああっ！
一つ一つの 角の形が違う！
Each of their horns has a different shape!
(研究者４)一番下のが
サンタナと 同じとしたなら➡
And if the one at the bottom is Santana...
...then who are the others?!
他の顔は 一体!?
Stroheim claimed the Germans discovered more
Pillar Men that are entombed somewhere in Europe.
シュトロハイムによれば
ドイツ軍は➡
さらなる 柱の男の遺跡を➡
ヨーロッパのどこかに
発見しているという｡
(研究者２)何!?
What?!
Given that these four faces are arranged vertically,
It's likely this is the hierarchy of the Pillar Men!
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)
この４つの顔は 縦に並んだ
位置関係から考えて➡
恐らく 柱の男たちの
身分関係を示している！
As Stroheim pleaded with us using his dying words,
Jojo and I must fly to Rome to meet with a man...
これから 私とジョジョは
シュトロハイムの遺言に従い➡
ある人物に会いに
ローマに飛ぶ｡
その人物とは…➡
And that man is...
あのウィル･Ａ･ツェペリの孫➡
...the grandson of Will A. Zeppeli...
...Caesar Zeppeli!
シーザー･ツェペリ！
君 どこから 来たんだい？
Miss, where are you from?
I see you're admiring the fountain.
Would you like me to snap your picture?
噴水を背景に
写真を撮ってあげようか？
(女性)えっ!?
(ﾊﾄの鳴きまね)
The birds in this country really seem to like me.
この国の鳥たちは
人懐っこいね～｡
男は やな感じだけどさ～！
It's a shame the men are such creeps!
ふん！
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)こら お前たち！➡
Enough, you two!
Now that you've met, you could at least talk a little!
紹介は済んだのに
お互い 挨拶ぐらいせんか!?
Mr. Speedwagon, let me be totally honest with you.
スピードワゴンさん
この際だ はっきり 言おう｡
50年前
俺の祖父に起こった 悲劇は！
After the tragedy that befell my grandfather fifty years ago...
...my father inherited his burden, and so he spent
his entire life chasing the shadow of the stone mask!
俺の父が 受け継ぎ
父は 生涯 石仮面の謎を追った！
The blood bonds among Italian families are tight-knit,
more than any other people in the world!
俺たち イタリア人は➡
一族を思う気持ちが
どの民族よりも 強い！
それを 誇りにしているから
受け継ぐのだ！
We take pride in our heritage, following their example!
As I continue to do!
俺も同様だ！
だが その男はどうだ!?
And what about him?
You told me he didn't know a thing about
his own grandfather until three months ago!
３か月前まで
自分の祖父のことを➡
何一つ
知らなかったというではないか！
いいかげんなやつだ！
気に食わん！
He's an irresponsible fool, and undignified!
何だ？ てめえ！
What's that, asshole?
You better watch your mouth!
言葉に 気を付けろよ！
シーザー 待ちたまえ！
Caesar, wait!
Jojo didn't know anything because I never told him!
ジョジョには 私が
全て 秘密にしていたからなのだ｡
はぁ…｡
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)ああ…｡
それは いいとしよう｡
And apart from that...
俺は そいつが ストレイツォや
柱の男と戦ったというから➡
I heard that he supposedly beat Straits and the man from the Pillar...
...so I waited in the hotel restaurant to see what kind of man he was.
どんな すごい男が
来たのかと思って➡
ホテルのレストランで 待った｡
But after testing his Ripple, I was utterly disappointed.
だが 彼の波紋を試してみて
がっかりしたよ！
くっ！
その兄ちゃんの波紋は 弱すぎる！
This child's Ripple is far too weak!
くっ…｡
柱の男には➡
His victory over the man in the Pillar was nothing but a fluke.
きっと まぐれで
勝ったにすぎなかったのだろう｡
こっ…｡
俺は➡
I have no desire to fight alongside this ape!
こんなやつと組むのは
ごめんだぜ！
Caesar, that's because Jojo's Ripple has never been properly trained...
シーザー！
それは ジョジョの波紋が➡
訓練されていないから…｡
ヘヘヘヘ…
じいさん もう遅いぜ｡
Uncle, it's too late for that now.
You asshole, I'm gonna beat you to a pulp!
この野郎
きっちりと ぶちのめしてやる！
Can't let you do that.
無理だね…｡
(女性)ああっ！
お前の波紋では
この女の子にさえ 勝てやせん｡
You couldn't even beat this girl with that pathetic Ripple of yours.
ヘヘヘヘ… ならば てめえは
このハトにさえ 勝てやしねえぜ！
Well, you couldn't even beat this pigeon!
フフフ…｡
(女性)ん…｡
あっ！ くっ…｡
ぐ～！
おちょくってるのか!?
Are you trying to mess with me?!
I like to make fun of people,
but that doesn't give you the right to mock me!
俺は からかうのは好きだが➡
からかわれるのは
大っ嫌いだぜ！
ぐあっ… うう…｡
うぐぐ…｡
Y-You... used the Ripple on this girl when you kissed her!
こ… これは
この子を キスの波紋で…｡
I'll say it again, you couldn't even beat this girl.
もう一度言う
お前は その娘にさえ 勝てんとな｡
S-Should I stop them?
《と… 止めるべきか…➡
No, it might be harsh, but maybe it's better
for Jojo to lose here and learn his lesson.
いや… 厳しいようだが➡
ジョジョが負ければ
所詮 それまで…》
ぐあっ！
ぐあああ～！
ふん！ それ見たことか！
See what I mean?
My grandfather died that day because
your grandfather couldn't hold his own in a fight!
俺のじいさんは お前の祖父が
足手まといになったおかげで➡
惨死したのだ！
And I'm expected to shame myself by
allying with a descendant of his bloodline?!
そんな 血統の男と
仲間になれるか？
Caesar, you've done enough!
シーザー！ それは言い過ぎだ！
て… てめえ！
Y-You prick...
Insulting me is one thing, yet you had to
bring my dead grandfather into this?
俺のことのみならず➡
死んだじいさんにまで 侮辱を！
許せねえ！
You'll pay for that!
I have the an ability to defeat the Pillar Men...
with a devastating coup de grâce!
俺には
柱の男どもを倒す術がある！
必殺の術が！
奥義 波紋シャボンランチャー！
My secret Ripple Bubble Launcher!
おおっ!?
I've hidden a special mix of soap water in my gloves and clothing to create Ripple Bubbles!
俺の手袋や コスチュームには➡
至る所に シャボンのための
特殊せっけん水が 仕込んである！
食らって 田舎へ帰りな！
ジョースター！
Let this wash you away to where you came from, Joestar!
おおおおっ！
ぐあ～！
うう…｡
ぐっ… はぁ… はぁ…｡
フッ 気絶しなかったのは
褒めてやるが➡
I applaud you for not losing consciousness...
お前の波紋では
俺のシャボンバリアーは 割れん！
...but your Ripple won't be able to break my bubble shield.
And look at that, you're already out of breath.
そして 見たことか
もう 呼吸を乱している｡
You should just take a short breather in there.
しばらく 苦しみな！
Now you're gonna say "Signorina, let me undo my Ripple's magic."
てめえは ｢シニョリーナ
波紋の魔術を解いてやる｣と言う｡
Now, Signorina, let me undo my Ripple's magic...
どれ シニョリーナ
波紋の魔術を解いてやるよ…｡
はっ！
おお… おお… あっ！
(ｼｰｻﾞｰ･ｼﾞｮｾﾌ)はぁ… はぁ…｡
さっき 首を絞められたとき➡
I used the Ripple to stuff a pigeon in her mouth when she had her hands around my throat!
女の子の口の中に
波紋を食らわした小バトを➡
入れておいたのだ！
ぬぅ!?
もう一度キスして 波紋を解くと
読んでいたんでなぁ｡
I just knew that you'd kiss her again to undo
your Ripple, you shameless casanova!
このスケコマシ！
もう一度 言うぜ｡
I'll say it again... You couldn't even beat a pigeon!
てめえは
ハトにさえ 勝てねえのさ！
ふん！
フフッ｡
ふぅ… やれやれ｡
What a bother...
Come on, what's with this guy?
《ちょっと!? 何？ こいつ～！➡
What kind of guy strikes a pose just to sit in a freaking chair?
普通 椅子 座るのに
こんな キザなポーズとるか!?➡
He's seriously making me mad!
まったく 気に障る野郎だぜ！➡
He's only getting away with this because I don't have
a special move like that Bubble Launcher yet!
俺が この野郎に
でかい面させているのは➡
俺に シャボンランチャーのような
必殺技がないからだ！➡
何か 考えなくっちゃあな！》
I gotta think of something, quick!
《でも 努力するのは嫌いで
めんどっちいし➡
But all that work sure seems like a pain in the ass...
けっ 俺の得意なカードで
思いっ切り ふんだくってやれ！》
I'll just have to show him who's boss with my favorite card trick!
おい ジョジョ 何だ？ これは｡
ちゃんと 配らんか！
Hey Jojo, what are you doing? Shuffle those cards properly.
Huh? What are you talking about?
ん？ 何のことだ？
おっ！
ちゃ～んと 配れと言ったのだ！
I said shuffle them properly!
いかさまは許さん！
No cheating!
あら！ あららら…｡
Oh no, he figured me out!
いか～ん バレちゃった～！
もっとも 貴様は こんな
ずる賢い手を 使わなきゃあ➡
Though I suppose there's no way
you could ever beat me without cheating.
この俺に 勝てんがな｡
So what did you plan on looking at
with the mirror attached to your shoe?!
じゃあ てめえの靴に
くっついてる鏡で➡
何を見てんだ!? こら！
Watch your mouth, hick!
うるさい！ やるか!? 田舎者！
Bring it on, casanova!
何だと!? このイモ！
Caesar!
シーザー君！
(ｼｰｻﾞｰ･ｼﾞｮｾﾌ)うっ…｡
君は 一体 昼すぎから
８時間も 何を待っているのだね？
What is it that you've been waiting for since eight o'clock?
What am I waiting for?
何を待っているだって？
あれを待っていたのさ！
I was waiting for that car!
ああっ！
何だ!? あいつは ドイツ軍だ！
What? A German officer?!
Looks like he got the okay.
ＯＫが出たようだ｡
えっ!?
柱の男は
ドイツ軍が警備している｡
This man is part of a German security detail.
He's going to be our guide.
そこへ 彼が案内してくれるのだ｡
ぬあにぃぃ～っ!?
What?!
♬～
イタリアとドイツは
同盟国なのだぜ！
Remember, Italy and Germany are allies!
The Germans want to study the power of my Ripple for science!
そして ドイツ軍は➡
この俺の波紋を
科学的に 研究したがっている｡
柱の男を
見せてもいいという許可が➡
The only reason an Englishman like you will even be able to see the Pillar Men...
イギリス人の君たちに出たのも➡
...is because I asked the Germans to do me a favor, Jojo!
このシーザーが 一生懸命
頼んだからなのだよ ジョジョ｡
Mr. Speedwagon, we'd like to hear any information you have.
(ﾏﾙｸ)スピードワゴンさん
あなた方の情報が 欲しいのです｡
If we work together, we can find a way to deal with them before they awaken!
やつらが目覚める前に 協力して
対抗策を見つけましょう！
おい マルク｡
Hey, Mark...
ところで
この 祖国の恋人は 元気か？
How is your girlfriend doing back at home?
ええ まあ…｡
そ… それがですね｡
Oh, well, about that...
来週 ドイツに帰ったら
結婚するんす 僕たち｡
We're getting married when I go back to Germany next week!
ホントかい!?
マンマミヤー！
Really?!
Mama Mia, that's wonderful news!
そいつは めでたい！
I actually helped set him up with his girlfriend in Germany, you know!
こいつの彼女 この俺が手伝って
ドイツで ナンパしたんですよ！
なっ！
デ… デヘヘヘ！
H-Hey, eyes on the road!
おい！
ちゃんと 前見て 運転しろ！
And get your filthy hands off the driver!
ハンドルに
頭 こすりつけてるんじゃねえ！
By the way, Jojo...
ところで ジョジョ？
Do you happen to have a girl?
お宅は 彼女いるのかい？
ふん…｡
いるわけないよねえ!?
Of course you don't!
What kind of woman would tolerate your abrasive personality?
この いいかげんな性格を
好きになる 女の子なんて｡
Nessie would be easier to find than the right woman for you!
ネッシー 探すのより
骨が折れるぜ｡
ハハハハッ！
《ちくしょ～ この野郎！➡
Damn this guy, he's so full of himself...
図に乗ってよ！➡
I'm gonna come up with an amazing special move,
and then I'll rub it in his face!
今に 飛び切りの必殺技を
考え出して➡
目にもの見せてやるぜ！》
(兵士１)
見ろ！ 様子がおかしいぞ！
Look, something's wrong!
(兵士２)な… 何だ!? ありゃ～！
W-What is that?!
Settle down!
(幹部)落ち着けィ！ こいつは
紫外線の照射を 浴びているのだ！
We have them surrounded by ultraviolet light, they can't move!
動けん！
一体 何なのか 注意して調べろ！
Now go and see what the hell's going on!
(兵士３)はっ！
Yes, sir!
We discovered some important info when
Stroheim's unit was wiped out in Mexico.
《メキシコの シュトロハイム隊の
全滅は 良い教訓となった｡➡
早いとこ
この岩っころを 切り出して➡
We have to keep this excavation moving, that way we can
get this tomb into a secure shelter within German borders.
ドイツ国内の シェルターに
入れちまわないとな》
(兵士３)
一体 どうなっているのだ!?
What the hell happened, though?
ちょうど 影になっていて
よく見えないぞ…｡
It's too dark to see a thing.
(兵士２)のぞいてみろよ｡
(兵士３)ああ…｡
Look closely.
(風の音)
(兵士３)な… 何か 音が…➡
I think I heard something...
ぐあっ！ かか…｡
(兵士４)うわ～！ 角が！
A horn?!
O-Oh no, it's...
ま… まさか こいつ!?
(幹部)目覚めている！➡
It's awakening!
紫外線の照射量を
もっと 多くしろ！
Increase the intensity of the ultraviolet lights!
Sir!
(兵士５)はっ！
(兵士２)うぎゃっ！
(兵士１)ぐわあっ！
(兵士たち)うわ～！
(幹部)ううっ！
He's blocking out the lights with blood and gore!
ち… 血と脳しょうで
紫外線の照明を 影にした‼
♬～
I can tell how the world has changed during
my slumber from the screams of these weaklings.
(ﾜﾑｳ)私の眠ってる間➡
外の世界が
どのように 変わったか➡
この 貧弱な発明を見て
想像できるな｡
しゃ… しゃべった!?
I-It spoke!
You cannot hold back the wrath of Wham with false sunlight!
(ﾜﾑｳ)作った光で このワムウを
縛ったままにできるか!?
(兵士４)うわ～！ 手が…｡
Our hands!
(兵士たち)くっついている！
They're stuck together!
ああ… ひいっ！
(幹部)ひ… ひい…｡
(兵士たち)うわっ！ 吸われる…｡
ワムウ！
Wham!
Awaken, my masters!
目覚めたまえ！
我が あるじたちよ！
有名な真実の口が 柱の男の眠る
地下への入り口だったのか！
The entrance to the Pillar Men's chamber is
the world-renowned "Mouth of Truth?"
How startling! The air feels very ominous...
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)ううむ 強烈！
不気味な妖気だ！➡
Caesar, have you tried using the Ripple on the sleeping Pillar Men?
シーザー 眠っている柱の男に
波紋を試してみたのかね？
波紋は 対生物能力！
The Ripple is only intended for use on living things.
岩石になっているやつらは
無機質！
Technically, they're not alive when they're stone.
目覚めてからでなければ 通じぬ｡
It won't work on them unless they've awoken.
ああ…｡
Hey, isn't the army supposed to be watching this place?
おい 軍隊が警備しているんだろ!?
どこにいるんだ!?
どこにもいねえじゃんよ！
Where are they?
I don't see anybody! It's too quiet in here!
静かすぎるぜ！
お前が うるせえんだ｡
Maybe you're just too loud.
I-It's strange...
お… おかしい｡
ん？
ここにいるはずの
我が軍の 見張り番がいない！
The guards that should be stationed here are gone.
何!?
ふん！
What?
(物音)
でぇ～！
おい 今 俺 何か 踏んづけたぞ！
Hey, I just stepped in something! And it's super disgusting!
すっげえ 気持ち悪いの！
What the hell is it?!
何だ？ これは！
(ﾏﾙｸ)ああっ！
こ… これは!?
人間の皮だ！
Th-This is-!
Human skin!
Th-They're all dead!
ぜ… 全滅しているぞ！
まさか!? うわ～！
There's no way!
Hey, German guy! Don't go that way!
おい ドイツ野郎！
そっちへ 行くんじゃあねえ！
There's something over there!
何か 潜んでいるぞ！
(ﾏﾙｸ)うわ～！
W-What the-?!
な… 何だ!?
なんてことだ！
Unbelievable! Th-They've...
こ… こいつらは!?
目覚めている！
They've awakened!
逃げろ マルク～‼
Run, Mark!
ああ… ああっ！
ああっ！
マルク～！
Mark!
ああ…｡
うあ… ああ…｡
マルク！
(ﾏﾙｸ)ああ…➡
Mark!
Caesar... Caesar!
シーザー… シーザー…｡
マルク～！
Mark!
くっ！
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)やつらは➡
They're not even acknowledging our presence!
我々を 気にも留めていない！
They're paying as much attention to the German boy they just killed...
ぶつかり その身を裂いた
ドイツ青年に対する➡
彼らの気持ちは➡
...as a man would pay to an ant that he just stepped on!
人間が アリを踏んでも
気付かないのと同じなのだ！
ぐっ…｡
It appears that night has fallen for now, Wham...
(ｶｰｽﾞ)
外は闇夜のようだな ワムウ…｡
(ﾜﾑｳ)はい カーズ様｡
これから いかがなされましょう？
Yes, Master Cars.
What shall we do?
Is it not obvious?
(ｴｼﾃﾞｨｼ)
当然 この世の いずこかにある➡
We shall head out in search of the Red Stone of Aja,
hidden somewhere in this world.
エイジャの赤石を
探しに行くのだ！➡
あと 一息よ！➡
We're nearly there!
We simply need to place the Red Stone of Aja
into this Stone Mask, and its power will be ours!
エイジャの赤石を
これに はめ込めば➡
石仮面は完成する！
But Master AC/DC, the world of mankind
has changed so much during our slumber.
しかし エシディシ様➡
人間どもの世界は
相当 変化している様子｡➡
The Roman Empire once held the Red Stone...
かつて 赤石は
ローマ皇帝が持っていると➡
いわれていましたが➡
...but that empire and their civilization have likely fallen.
その時代は もはや
続いてはおらぬでしょう｡
Then we must first locate the Red Stone.
(ｶｰｽﾞ)では まずは 赤石の行方を
探さねばならぬということか｡
The Red Stone which the Roman Empire greatly desired.
ローマの皇帝を魅了した
その赤石｡
Mankind would not lose track of something like that.
人間たちの うわさに
上らぬはずはありませぬ｡➡
I swear to locate it for you.
必ずや 探し出してみせます｡
There's plenty of time.
(ｶｰｽﾞ)時間はある｡
(ｴｼﾃﾞｨｼ)今は とりあえず➡
For the time being, let's head overseas to see
just how much the human world has changed.
人間世界の変化ぶりを 見学に
外界に出るとしよう｡
(ｶｰｽﾞ)うむ…｡
はっ！
(ｴｼﾃﾞｨｼ)ワムウ！
Wham!
Fool, what is the meaning of this?!
おのれ！ 何をするか!?
Wait, AC/DC!
(ｶｰｽﾞ)待てい！ エシディシ！
Forgive me, Master Cars!
(ﾜﾑｳ)失礼を カーズ様…｡
(ｶｰｽﾞ)ワムウ！ お前が 自分の影に
入られるのを 極端に嫌い➡
Wham, I know how much you hate it when
someone stands within your shadow...
無意識のうちに 反射攻撃を
してしまうのを 忘れておった｡
...but I forgot how you attack on instinct
when someone invades that space.
何しろ 2,000年ぶりだからな｡
It has been two millennia, after all...
I have attacked the ones that I am meant to serve!
(ﾜﾑｳ)主人に対する
無礼を働きました｡➡
Please punish me however you see fit!
何なりと 罰をお与えください｡
(ｶｰｽﾞ)フッ… いいや
なぜ そんなことができよう｡➡
No, I couldn't imagine it.
I'm counting on that warrior's instinct of yours
as we move towards our goal.
私は お前の
今のような 闘争の士気を➡
何よりも 頼りにしている｡➡
It was my fault for entering your shadow.
お前の影に入った
私が悪かったのだ｡➡
Forgive me, Wham.
許してくれ ワムウ｡
Master Cars...
(ﾜﾑｳ)カーズ様｡
(ｶｰｽﾞ)フッ… 行くぞ ワムウ｡
Let's go, Wham.
Right!
(ﾜﾑｳ)はっ！
ああ… シーザー！
Caesar!
Kill me! Hurry up and kill me!
殺してくれ！
は… 早く 僕を殺してくれ！
Mark!
マルク！
T-The pain is excruciating...
だ… だんだん
痛みを感じてきた｡➡
お… 恐ろしい…｡➡
I'm terrified...
I was numb at first, but now it's beginning to hurt a lot!
マヒしている所に
しだいしだいに痛みが…➡
は… 早く
僕を殺してほしい シーザー！
Now hurry up and do it, Caesar!
マルク！
Mark!
T-There's nothing we can do!
《ど… どうしようもねえ！➡
There's nothing left we can do to save him!
この青年に対して
何もしてやれねえ➡
We're helpless!
この俺たちの 無力さ！➡
I've never felt so useless!
この行き場のない 絶望感は…！》
シ… シーザー…｡
C-Caesar...
コォー…｡
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)お前…｡
You...
ありがとう… シーザー…｡
Thank you, Caesar...
くっ…｡
う… ううっ…｡
マルク！
Mark!
くっ…｡
マルクは ただの若者だった…｡
Mark was just an ordinary young man.
He was no different from anyone else.
普通の人々と同じに 家族を愛し➡
He loved his family, his girl, and his country...
恋人を愛し 国を愛し
仕事に 一生懸命の➡
He worked hard at his job, just like anyone else his age.
ただの青年だった｡
He had his whole life ahead of him!
ただの若者だった！
Caesar!
シーザー！
ジョジョ お前は引っ込んでろ！
Jojo... stay out of this!
I'm putting an end to this!
俺が 片をつける！
I couldn't live with myself otherwise!
片をつけなきゃあ 気が済まない！
♬(ｴﾝﾃﾞｨﾝｸﾞﾃｰﾏ)
♬ Along the drifting cloud,
Along the drifting cloud, the eagle searching down on the land
♬ the eagle
searching down on the land
♬ Catching the swirling wind,
Catching the swirling wind, the sailor sees the rim of the land
♬ the sailor
sees the rim of the land
♬ The eagle's dancing wings
The eagle's dancing wings create, as weather spins out of hand
♬ create as weather spins
out of hand
♬～
Go closer hold the land, feel partly no more than grains of sand
♬ Go closer, hold the land,
♬ feel partly no more than
grains of sand
♬ We stand to lose all time,
We stand to lose all time, a thousand answers by in our hand
♬ a thousand answers by
in our hand
Next to your deeper fears, we stand surrounded by million years
♬ Next to your deeper fears,
♬ we stand surrounded by
million years
♬ I'll be the roundabout
I'll be the roundabout
♬ The words
will make you out'n'out
The words will make you out and out
♬ I'll be the roundabout
I'll be the roundabout
♬ The words
will make you out'n'out
The words will make you out and out
Next Episode
Even I'm getting tired of talking!
I told you to continue!
He's rotten!
A clan of Ripple users...
My secret, the Holy Sandstorm!
Episode 15:
"A Hero's Worth"
あ～ しゃべるのも
だるくなってきた｡
(ﾜﾑｳ)
続けろ！ と言っているのだ！
やつは クズだった！
(ｶｰｽﾞ)波紋の一族…｡
(ﾜﾑｳ)闘技 神砂嵐！